creditcardinsider.com 2019-08-22

# Privacy Policy - Credit Card Insider

Credit Card Insider receives compensation from advertisers whose products may be mentioned on this page. Advertiser relationships do not affect card evaluations. Advertising partners do not edit or endorse our editorial content. Content is accurate to the best of our knowledge when it's published. Learn more in our Editorial Guidelines.

Credit Card Insider takes your privacy seriously. This privacy policy describes what personal information we collect and how we use it.

**Routine Information Collection**

All web servers track basic information about their visitors. This information includes, but is not limited to, IP addresses, browser details, timestamps and referring pages. None of this information can personally identify specific visitors to this site. The information is tracked for routine administration and maintenance purposes.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

Where necessary, Credit Card Insider ** ** uses cookies to store information about a visitor’s preferences and history in order to better serve the visitor and/or present the visitor with customized content.

Advertising partners and other third parties may also use cookies, scripts and/or web beacons to track visitors to our site in order to display advertisements and other useful information. Such tracking is done directly by the third parties through their own servers and is subject to their own privacy policies.

When you use our Services, we collect certain information by automated or electronic means, using technologies such as cookies, pixel tags and web beacons, browser analysis tools, and web server logs. As you use our Services, your browser and devices communicate with servers operated by us, our business partners and services providers to coordinate and record the interactivity and fill your requests for services and information.

The information from cookies and related technology is stored in web server logs and also in web cookies kept on your computers or mobile devices, which are then transmitted back to our Services by your computers or mobile devices. These servers are operated and the cookies managed by us, our business partners or our service providers.

For example, when you access our Services, Credit Card Insider and our service providers may place cookies on your computers or mobile devices. These cookies may include means for tracking your Transaction Information with a Merchant and may include tracking technology from third-party affiliate-network operators like LinkShare and Conversant. Cookies allow us to recognize you when you return, and track and target your interests in order to provide a customized experience. They also help us provide a customized experience and help us to detect certain kinds of fraud. A “ _cookie_ ” is a small amount of information that a web server sends to your browser that stores information about your account, your preferences, and your use of the Services. Some cookies contain serial numbers that allow us to connect your activity with the Services with other information we store about you in your profile or as related to your other interactions with the Services.

Some cookies are temporary, whereas others may be configured to last longer. “ _Session_ ” cookies are temporary cookies used for various reasons, such as to manage page views. Your browser usually erases Session cookies once you exit your browser. “ _Persistent_ ” cookies are more permanent cookies that are stored on your computers or mobile devices even beyond when you exit your browser. We use Persistent cookies for a number of purposes, such as retrieving certain information you have previously provided (such as your user id if you asked to be remembered), and storing your preferences.

Pixel tags and web beacons are tiny graphic images placed on website pages or in our emails that allow us to determine whether you have performed specific actions. When you access these pages or open email messages, the pixel tags and web beacons generate a notice of that action to us, or our service providers. These tools allow us to measure response to our communications and improve our web pages and promotions.

We collect many different types of information from cookies and other technologies. For example, we may collect information from the devices you use to access our Services, your operating system type or mobile device model, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone of your device. Browsers routinely send these types of information to web servers. Our server logs also record the Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses of the devices you use to interact with the Services. An IP address is a unique identifier that devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. We may also collect information about the website you were visiting before you came to our Services and the website you visit after you leave our Services, if this information is supplied to us by your browser.

In many cases, the information we collect using cookies and other tools is used in non-identifiable ways, without any reference to Personal Information. For example, we use information we collect about users to optimize our Services and understand its traffic and usage patterns. In other cases, we associate the information we collect using cookies and related technologies with Personal Information. In that case, this Privacy Policy governs how we use that information.

Credit Card Insider has relationships with third party advertising companies to place advertisements on our behalf onto other websites, and to perform tracking and reporting functions for our Services and our advertisements. We do not share Personal Information with third party advertising companies; however, these third parties may automatically collect information about your visit to our Services and other websites, your IP address, your ISP and the browser you use to visit our Services. They do this by using cookies, clear gifs and other technologies. Information collected may be used, among other things, to deliver advertising targeted to your interests and to better understand the usage and visitation of our Services and the other websites tracked by these third parties. This Privacy Policy does not cover the collection methods or use of the information collected by these third parties, and Credit Card Insider is not responsible for cookies or clear gifs in third party ads. We encourage you to review the privacy policies or statements of these third party advertising companies to learn more about their use of cookies and other technologies. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by third party advertisers, please visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org](https://www.networkadvertising.org/).

We also use third party services, such as Google Analytics, to help us understand how visitors interact with our website and to help improve our user experience.

**Controlling Your Privacy**

Note that you can change your browser settings to disable cookies if you have privacy concerns. Disabling cookies for all sites is not recommended as it may interfere with your use of some sites. The best option is to disable or enable cookies on a per-site basis. Consult your browser documentation for instructions on how to block cookies and other tracking mechanisms.

**Special Note About Google Advertising**

Any advertisements served by Google, Inc., and affiliated companies may be controlled using cookies. These cookies allow Google to display ads based on your visits to this site and other sites that use Google advertising services. Learn how to [opt out of Google’s cookie usage](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). As mentioned above, any tracking done by Google through cookies and other mechanisms is subject to Google’s own privacy policies.

**Compensation Disclaimer**

Please note that Credit Card Insider has financial relationships with some of the merchants mentioned here. Credit Card Insider may be compensated if consumers choose to utilize the links located throughout the content on this site and generate sales for the said merchant.

**Contact Information**

Concerns or questions can be directed through our contact form for further clarification.
